A Guide to the Papers of Rear Admiral Walter C. Ansel, 1924-1974
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
- Documents of the German Military during World War II
  - Admiral Commanding France (Adm. Frankr. - Kriegsmarine)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to Naval Commands of the Netherlands, English Channel, Northern France, etc..., 23 Oct. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 45)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to Naval Command of the English Channel, 27 Oct. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 46)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to Gruppe West, O.K.M., and Skl., 3 Nov. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 47)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to Naval Port Commands at Le Harve, Boulogne, Calais, Dunkirk, etc., 6 Nov. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 48)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to Naval Port Commander Boulogne and Dunkirk, 7 Nov. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 49)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to Naval Commands of the English Channel, Netherlands, Northern France, and the Naval Port Commands at Rotterdam, Antwerp, etc., 9 Nov. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 50)
    - Adm. Frankr. memos to O.K.M. and Skl, Naval Port Command at Dunkirk and the English Channel, 11 Nov. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 51)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to Naval Command Staff of the Netherlands, Naval Commands of the English Channel, and Northern France, 13 Nov. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 52)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to O.K.M. and Skl., 19 Nov. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 53)
    - Adm. Frankr. memos to Naval Command of the English Channel; Naval Port Commands of Calais and the Naval Command of the English Channel, 18 Nov. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 54)
    - Adm. Frankr. memos to Naval Command of the English Channel; O.K.M. and 1 /Skl. Naval Command West and other naval departments., 21 Nov. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 55)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to Naval Command of the English Channel, 23 Nov. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 56)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to Naval Command of the English Channel, 24 Nov. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 57)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to Naval Command of the English Channel, 29 Nov. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 58)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to all naval departments, 9 Dec. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 59)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to Chief of Skl., 16 Dec. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 60)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to Skl., 17 Dec. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 61)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to O.K.M. and Skl., 28 Dec. 1940 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 62)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to all naval commands, 2 Jan. 1941 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 63)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to Gruppe West, 30 Jan. 1941 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 64)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to Naval Commands of the English Channel, and the Netherlands, 2 Feb. 1941 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 65)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to O.K.M. and Skl., 3 Feb. 1941 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 66)
    - Adm. Frankr. memo to Naval Command of the Western France, Naval Port Commands at Brest, Lorient, etc..., 7 Feb. 1941 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 67)
  - Port Commanders, Ocean Commands, Naval Command Posts, Shipyards, Transport Chiefs, and Commanding Admirals
    - Admiral Commanding the Ocean Post for Amphibious Group One, memo to Naval Command in the Netherlands, 23 Feb. 1942 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Admiral Commanding the Ocean Headquarters to: Gruppe West, Naval Port Commands Dunkirk and Antwerp, Naval Port Command Antwerp, Naval Command West, 20 May 1941, 23 May 1941, 31 Jul. 1941, 16 Sept. 1941 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Amphibious Chief report to O.K.M., 26 Sept. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Commander of Sea Defenses at the Port of Calais memo to: Naval Port Command Antwerp, Naval Port Commands at Rotterdam, Antwerp, etc., 3 Sept. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Commander of Sea Defenses of Northern Holland memo to: Naval Command Holland, Naval Command Netherlands (2 memos), 6 Jan. 1941, 26 Apr. 1941, 20 Mar. 1941 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Commander of Motorboat Staff memo to O.K.M. and Skl., 1-13 Sept. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Counter Intelligence of the Navy memo to O.K.M., 14 Aug. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Flag Officer Commanding Destroyers memo to Gruppe West and O.K.M., 6 Aug. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Admiral Commanding the Fleet memo to Gruppe West, Admiral Commanding France, and Naval Command of the Netherlands, 28 Aug. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Chief of Staff of the Admiral Commanding the Fleet memo to the tactical group of the General Staff..., 2 Sept. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Commander of Fleet Transport C operational brief number Three, 13 Oct. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Fortress Constructions Staff memo to Naval Command Staff of the Netherlands, 15 Oct. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Group Adminstration report on the Military Question of wartime construction of ships to Naval Departments XI, A, VI, and May, 10 Jan. 1941 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Inspector of Naval Ship Building memo to Gruppe West, Gruppe East, etc..., 23 Jul. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Main Office of Warship Construction memo to: Ob.d.M., Skl. and Navy Department A VI, 1/Skl. and Navy Department A VI, 2 Jul. 1940, 12 Aug. 1940, 18 Sept. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Naval Commander of Occupied Belgium and Northern France memo to 1/Skl, 23 Sept. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Naval Directive for Warship Construction memo to 1/Skl. and naval departments K III chef and A VI. Memo to 1/Skl., and Naval Departments A VI, M Wehr., K III Chef, 23 Aug. 1940, 4 Sept. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Motorboat Staff of the Navy memo to Admiral Commanding France, O.K.M., Skl., etc..., 12 Aug. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Naval Commanding the English Channel Command memos to: Naval Command Netherlands, Admiral Commanding France, O.K.M., Gruppe West, Admiral Commanding U-Boats, etc..., Admiral Commanding France, O.K.M., Gruppe West, etc., Naval Command of Northern France, 12 Jul. 1940, 30 Jul. 1940, 10 Aug. 1940, 19 Aug. 1940, 30 Sept. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Naval Officer Commanding the Netherlands, 14 Aug. 1940-20 Mar. 1942 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Naval Command Post Boulogne memos to: Naval Port Command Dieppe, Naval Commander of the English Channel (2 memos), 24 Sept. 1940, 30 Sept. 1940, 5 Oct. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Naval Command Post Calais memos to:Naval Command Headquarters, Naval Commander of the English Channel, 1/Skl., Admiral Commanding France and Naval Commander of the English Channel, port Command Ostend and Naval Commander of the English Channel, 7 Oct. 1940, 9 Oct. 1940, 24 Oct. 1940, 11 Nov. 1940, 12 Nov. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Naval Command Post Dunkirk memos to: Gruppe West, Naval Commander of the English Channel (2 memos), 1 Oct. 1940, 5 Oct. 1940, 22 Nov. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Naval Command Post Ostende memos to Naval Commander of the English Channel, 5, 12, 21 Oct. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Naval Command Post Rotterdam Memos to: Admiral Commanding Coastal Defense, Admiral Commanding the Netherlands, Costal Command Antwerp, 23 Apr. 1941, 17 Aug. 1941, 11 Oct. 1941 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Naval Headquarters memos to Skl., 31 Aug..., 30 Sept., 4 Oct. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Naval Port Command Amsterdam memo to Admiral Commanding the Netherlands, 25 Jan. 1941 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Naval Port Command Antwerp memos to Admiral Commanding the Netherlands, 22, 25, Feb., 6 Oct., 27 Nov., 8 Dec. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Naval Port Command Delfzijl memo to Admiral Commanding the Netherlands, 14 Dec. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Naval Port Command Holland, 7 Mar. 1941-21 Mar. 1942 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Naval Port Command Ijmuiden memo to Admiral Commanding the Netherlands, 25 Apr. 1941 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Naval Port Command Rotterdant memos, 16 Sept. 1940-20 Oct. 1941 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Naval Port Command Vlissingen memo to Admiral Commanding the Netherlands, 24 Mar. 1941-20 Mar. 1942 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Naval Shipyard Wilhelmshaven memos, 4 Jul. 1940-19 Aug. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Ocean Headquarters Antwerp memos, 28 Oct. 1940-12 Nov. 1941 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Ocean Headquarters Kiukamp memo to Naval Command West, 9 Oct. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Ocean Headquarters von Fischel memo to Gruppe West, 17 Sept. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Private Contractor from Antwerp, 27 Sept. 1941 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Security Commander West memos to: Admiral Commanding France, Gruppe West, 4 Feb. 1941, 28 Feb. 1941 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 39)
    - First Security Division to Admiral Commanding the Netherlands, 1941 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 40)
    - Shipyard Representative of France, 28 Aug. 1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 41)
    - Shipyard Representative of Belgium and the Netherlands memo to O.K.M., 29 Dec. 1941 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 42)
    - Transport Chiefs messages, 1940, 1941 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 43)
- German Military Reports
  - Battle for Crete
    - 4th Air Fleet report book (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 1)
    - 11th Paratrooper Corps Report Part I (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 2)
    - 11th Paratrooper Corps Report Part II (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 3)
    - General Ramke's report (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 4)
    - General Student's report to Reichmarchal Hermann Goering, Nov. 1942 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Log Book of the 5th Mountain Division Part I (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Log Book of the 5th Mountain Division Part II (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Log Book of the 5th Mountain Division Part III (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Log Book of the 5th Mountain Division Part I (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Log Book of the 5th Mountain Division Part II (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 2)
    - General Meimz's report (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 3)
    - General Ringel's report (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 4)
    - General Ringel's Log Book (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Reports
    - Air Reports of Airplanes over Water (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Assmann's report on a Plan for invasion of Crete (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Code Signals (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Malta. Plans for Invasion in 1942 by Junge and Wagenheim (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified reports about Crete (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Air Reports by the Naval Liason to the Airforce (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Changes in Fleet Command, 1939 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Common to all over Landings Removed (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Data for the Naval War Staff on the area in the East Sea between Germany and Russia (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Grand Admiral Raeder (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Naval Command of the English Channel reports (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Naval Command of the Netherlands reports (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Naval Command of Dunkirk reports (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Naval Construction Reports Part I, 1929-1939 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Naval Construction Reports Part II, 1929-1939 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Naval War Staff Report on Principles and Problems of the Navy Part I (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Naval War Staff Report on Principles and Problems of the Navy Part II (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Naval War Staff Report on War Against England (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Naval War Staff Report on Operation FELIX (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Notes on Warfare in North Africa (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Reich Leaders for the Occupied Netherlands Zone reports (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Records on the Situation Discussion of the Home Defense Department (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Record minutes of the meeting between Grand Admiral Raeder and the Fuehrer (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Restricted Cruiser Warfare throughly in Pan American Safety Zone, from proposed Legal (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Study of England, 27 May 1940 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Study of North Atlantic (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Submarines toward Halifax (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Sylt Experiments (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Time for Landings (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Unidentified Reports (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Operation Sea Lion
    - Armed Forces High Command report on Operation Sea Lion, 20 Jan. 1940 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Armed Forces High Command report on Invasion of England (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Air Force Command report (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Army High Command report, 25 Aug. 1940 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Army High Command report, 30 Aug. 1940 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 5)
    - The Fuehrer and Supply Commanders of the Wehrmacht. Directive #16, 16 Jul. 1940 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Air Force Report on Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Admiral Commanding France Plans #1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and 10 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Amphibious Transport Notes (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Artillery Support for Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Besiege of England, Plan 1 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Coastal Command in the Channel (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Diagrams of Landing Sites for Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Estimates of Landing Sites to be used in Sea Lion, 21 Oct. 1940 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Naval Group West Reports on Sea Lion. Part I (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Naval Group West Reports on Sea Lion. Part II (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Naval Group West Reports on Sea Lion. Part III (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Notes on Ground Conjuration, 28 and 30 Aug. 1940 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Record of Intensity of the Naval War Against England (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Record of Landing Prepartions. Part I (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Record of Landing Prepartions. Part II (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Report on Excercises for the Night Operation over the preparation for Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Report on Strength of the Enemy in English Ports (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Sea Lion Documents presented at the Nuremburg War Trials (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Special report on Dunkirk to Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Special report on Naval Index (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 26)
    - To Stop Enemy Troops in Action Near the Border by Transports (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Mine Sites in the English Channel (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Official Weather Reports (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Report on Sea Lion, 20 Jul. 1940 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Report on Sea Lion, 12 Sept. 1940 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Readiness of Port Commanders for Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Transportation fo men and Material fo Sea (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Transports built for Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Transports Estimates (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 8)
    - War Time Leadership toward England and a Sortie for Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Addresses made by the Ob.d.M. on Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Construction of Transports (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Distribution of Transports and their Locations (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Eventual Temporary Landing of Troops on the British Island (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 13)
    - O.K.M. report on Sea Lion. Part I (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 14)
    - O.K.M. report on Sea Lion. Part II (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Skl. report on Invasion of England. Part I (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Skl. report on Invasion of England. Part II (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Skl. report for Supplies and the Managment of Machines in the following Ports (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Skl. Log Book on Operation Sea Lion (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Skl. report on Operation Sea Lion. Part I (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Skl. report on Operation Sea Lion. Part II (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Skl. report on Operation Sea Lion. Part III (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Skl. report on Operation Sea Lion. Part IV (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 23)
    - 1/Skl. report on Operation Sea Lion., 26 Sept. 1940 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 24)
    - The Transport Block for the North and South in Foreign Canals (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 25)
- English, French, German Publications
  - English
    - "Battle for Britain" by the Air Ministry. Number 156, Aug. 1943 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Royal United Service Institute, May 1961 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 2)
  - French
    - La Revue Maritime, Oct. 1952 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 3)
    - La Revue Maritime, Nov. 1955 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Les Tentatives De Paix, 1939-1945 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 5)
  - German
    - Die Gebirg Struppe, Numbers 1, 2, 3, 1954 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Die Welt Als Geschicite, Numbers 1 and 4, 1953 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Marine Rundeschau, Jan. 1953 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Marine Rundeschau, Jan. 1954 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Marine Rundeschau, Jun. 1958 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Marine Rundeschau, Dec. 1958 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Wehr-Wissenschaftliche, Number 3, Mar. 1953 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Wehr-Wissenschaftliche, Number 3, Mar. 1956 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Wehr-Wissenschaftliche, Number 8, Aug. 1958 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Wehr-Wissenschaftliche, Number 3, Mar. 1959 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Vierteljahrshefte fur Zeitgeichicite, Number 4, Jul. 1954 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Vierteljahrshefte fur Zeitgeichicite, Number 4, Oct. 1954 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 17)
- German Wartime Publications
  - The wartime Command of the Axis Powers in the Mediterranean
    - Forward and Index (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Part I (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Part II (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Part III (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Part IV (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Part V (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 6)
- U.S, Military Publications
  - Re: German High Command
    - Guide to Foreign Military Studies, 1945-1954: Catalog and Index, by the U.S. Historical Division, 1954 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Guide to Captured German Records in the Custody of Department of the Army Agencies in the U.S., 1951 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Guide to Captured German Documents, Dec. 1952 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 3)
    - German Order of Battle. The War Office, 1944 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Griner Series, O.K.W., World War II. Historical Division in the European Command (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 5)
    - German Supreme Command in World War II. Historical Division in the European Command (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Reflections on the High Command Organization. Department of the Army Agencies in the U.S. (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Draft Entries in War Diary of Defense Branch of the Wehrmacht Operations: H.D.E.C., Aug-Nov 1940 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Review of the German High Command. H.D.E.C. Part I (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Review of the German High Command. H.D.E.C. Part II (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Review of the German High Command. H.D.E.C. Part III (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 11)
    - German Army High Command O.K.H. (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Relating to German Military Operations and Campaigns
    - U.S. Naval Intelligence Report on German Operation Sea Lion, 4 Feb. 1946 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Greiner "Series" Operation "Sealoewe" H.D.E.C. (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Operation "Sea Lion" H.D.E.C. (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Operation Sea Lion, 1939-1942. H.D.E.C. Part I, Sept. 1954 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Operation Sea Lion, 1939-1942. H.D.E.C. Part II, Sept. 1954 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Operation Sea Lion, 1939-1942. H.D.E.C. Part III, Sept. 1954 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Operation Sea Lion, 1939-1942. H.D.E.C. Part IV, Sept. 1954 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Operation Felix. H.D.E.C., 22 Oct. 1945 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Operation Barbarosa (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 9)
    - The German Campaign in Russia, 1940-1942. U.S. Army, Nov. 1955 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 10)
    - The German campaign in the Balkans, Spring 1941. U.S. Army, Nov. 1953 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Crete: Hitler's Secret. General Kurt Student, March 1962 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Answers to the Questions Concerning Greece, Crete, and Russia. H.D.E.C. (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Relating to the Military Departments of the German Armed Forces
    - Airborne Operations: A German Apprasial. Office of the Chief of Military History, Dept. Army, 1950 (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Evaluation of German Airborne Operations. H.D.E.C., 1954 (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Force General Order Numbers One to Forty Three. Rear Admiral A.G. Kirk Part I, 1943 (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Force General Order Numbers One to Forty Three. Rear Admiral A.G. Kirk Part II, 1943 (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Historical Turning Points in the German Air Force War Effort. Richard Suchenwirth. U.S.A.F., Jun. 1959 (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Von Rohden's Collection of Documents Part I (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Von Rohden's Collection of Documents Part II (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Von Rohden's Collection of Documents Part III (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Von Rohden's Collection of Documents Part IV (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Von Rohden's Collection of Documents Part V (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Von Rohden's Collection of Documents Part VI (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Von Rohden's Collection of Documents Part VII (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Von Rohden's Collection of Documents Part VIII (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Von Rohden's Collection of Documents Part IX (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 14)
- American Published Articles
  - "Adolf Hitler: A Personal Story by William L. Shirer," Look Magazine (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 1)
  - "The Amphibious Assault Fast, Flexible, and Powerful," By David S. Bill, Jr., Oct. 1962 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 2)
  - "The Battle of Crete," London Gazette, May 1962 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 3)
  - "Beachmaster-The Amphibious Combat Traffic Cops," By Lieutenant D.W. Orahood, U.S.N. U.S. Naval Institute Proceedings, Sept. 1966 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 4)
  - "Chance Now for Peace," U.S. News and World Report, Jun. 1969 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 5)
  - "Clausewitz, Cuba, and Command," by Capt. Paul R. Schratz. U.S Naval Institute Proceedings, Aug. 1964 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 6)
  - "Clouds over the Australian Sun," by Barbara Ward. New York Times Magazine, Nov. 4, 1962 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 7)
  - "Dunkirk-Miracle or Blunder?" by Col. G.C. Reinhardt. U.S. Army (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 8)
  - "A Force of Readiness," by Karl A. Schoun (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 9)
  - "The French Navy at Dunkirk, May-June 1940," by Jacques Mordal. U.S. Naval Institute Proceedings, Feb. 1959 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 10)